[MUSIC]
Hi, there this is James,
in this C# practice session,
you'll practice creating and
using properties in C#.
It reinforces what you learned in
stage 5 of the C# objects course.
If you find this practice session
too challenging to complete,
you might need to review that course.
See the teacher's notes for a link.
This practice session is the fifth in a
series of sessions where you'll build out
a media library console application.
Step by step,
you'll add features to the program.
Eventually you'll be able
to use C# to add, list, and
search for items like albums,
books, and movies,
whatever you want to have
cataloged in your media library.
In the previous practice sessions
we created a class hierarchy for
our program's media types and
we used encapsulation and arrays to
improve the design of our program.
In this practice session we'll see how we
can replace class fields with properties.
And use computer properties
to add atributes whose values
are based upon other atributes.
Go ahead and open your work space from
the previous practice session, or
you can open the work space that
I´ve attached to this video.
If you want,
you can download the project files in
order to use an external editor or
IDE like Visual Studio.
Before we go about replacing
our class fields to properties,
let's reveal what we'd want to do this?
In the C# objects course,
three reasons were discussed.
First, properties have getters and
setters which gives us a way to
associate code with the get in and
or setting of the property's value.
Second, properties make
debugging easier as you can set
break points in gitters or setters.
And third, properties help future proof
our code by encapsulating our fields.
This gives us a way to change
the underlying implementation of
our class without changing how
consumers interact with it.
Our media library program contains
four media type related classes.
A Media Type base class, and
three Media Type subclasses—album,
book, and movie.
For your first challenge,
replace each public field with a property,
in the MediaType base class, and
Album, Book, and Movie subclasses.
Use either the regular C# property syntax,
or
the more concise auto-implemented
property syntax.
Also use private setters for
fields that should be read-only and
initialize those properties
via the constructor.
And, in the media type base class,
initialize the loanee and
onloan properties and line to an empty
string and false, respectively.
And that's your first challenge.
Good luck, and
we'll see you in the next video,
where I'll walk through my solution.